{
    "id": "494bfea0786d4563afaaf106e28e5176",
    "title": "Idioms Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The company has turned the ................................. and its prospects are looking up.",
            "description": "To turn a / the corner is to pass a critical situation.",
            "answers": [
                "corner",
                "highway",
                "junction"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He cleverly turned the ........................................ on his opponent.",
            "description": "To turn the tables is to turn a position of disadvantage to one of advantage.",
            "answers": [
                "game",
                "match",
                "tables"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He is a short tempered guy but his ...................................... is in the right place.",
            "description": "To have your heart in the right place is to have the right intentions.",
            "answers": [
                "mind",
                "heart",
                "soul"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The problem of unemployment is a hard ......................................... to crack.",
            "description": "A hard nut to crack is a difficult problem.",
            "answers": [
                "ball",
                "nut",
                "shell"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He found himself in .......................................... water over his comments about the prophet.",
            "description": "To find yourself in hot water is to be in a difficult situation.",
            "answers": [
                "cold",
                "hot",
                "lukewarm"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Scientists searching for life on other planets may be on a ............................................... chase.",
            "description": "A wild goose chase is a foolish and hopeless search.",
            "answers": [
                "wild cat",
                "wild goose",
                "wild parrot"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Once he became an established writer, he was content to rest on his ...................................",
            "description": "To rest on one's oars is to stop working after achieving success or finishing a task.",
            "answers": [
                "bed",
                "mattress",
                "oars"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The player was nursing an injury and it took the ........................................ out his sails.",
            "description": "To take the wind out of sails is to cause someone to lose energy or confidence.",
            "answers": [
                "steam",
                "wind",
                "force"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The manager took him to ........................................ for not meeting the deadlines.",
            "description": "To take somebody to task is to reprimand them.",
            "answers": [
                "job",
                "work",
                "task"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The police left no ...................................... unturned in their search for the missing boy.",
            "description": "To leave no stone unturned is to do everything possible.",
            "answers": [
                "stone",
                "brick",
                "boulder"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}